<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manvi Gupta</title>
    <link>https://manvi07.github.io/author/manvi-gupta/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://manvi07.github.io/author/manvi-gupta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Manvi Gupta</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://manvi07.github.io/images/icon_hu_e747e089a9e68c83.png</url>
      <title>Manvi Gupta</title>
      <link>https://manvi07.github.io/author/manvi-gupta/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manvi Gupta</title>
      <link>https://manvi07.github.io/author/manvi-gupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://manvi07.github.io/author/manvi-gupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Machine Learning Engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adobe.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Adobe India&lt;/a&gt;. I am a part of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://firefly.adobe.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Firefly &amp;amp; GenAI&lt;/a&gt; team.  I have completed my Bachelor in Technology (B.Tech.) in &lt;i&gt;Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/i&gt; from the &lt;a href = &#34;http://iitmandi.ac.in/&#34; target=_blank&gt; Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Mandi &lt;/a&gt; with my winter-semester 2019-2020 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rwth-aachen.de/&#34; target=_blank&gt; RWTH Aachen University Germany &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;!-- , where I got a chance to indulge in Masters-level courses &amp; research projects.--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- At Adobe, we work on the in-house Machine Learning Platform, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adobe.com/in/sensei.html&#34; target=_blank&gt; Sensei&lt;/a&gt;. Here, we combine the power of Cloud Technology and the ease of use of a platform to make it easier for researchers to focus on their ML research. More challenges kick in when handling the huge scale of requests, varied resource requirements and optimisations. --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Adobe, I contribute to our in-house AI platform, combining cloud technology with user-friendly tools to streamline research training. Scaling infrastructure, optimizing resources, and handling massive ML workloads keep things exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond Computer Science, I have a strong interest in Mathematics &amp;amp; Security. As a part of my B.Tech, I have worked on a wide range of projects ranging from Web Development to Deep Neural Networks. My Bachelor Thesis was on, &lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why Deep Learning Works?&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.co.in/citations?user=qZkww5oAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&#34; target=_blank&gt;Dr. Samar Agnihotri&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- I think of myself as a hard-working and fun-loving person, who makes sure to stick to the timelines. --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a mix of hard work and fun &amp;ndash; always on time, yet always up for an adventure. I love travelling to new places. When not working, find me enjoying nature, catching up with family and friends, or geeking out over science fiction. I have always been fascinated by the advancements shaping our future and believe that the only attitude that keeps one going is to never stop learning. Always happy to lend a hand (or a fun fact) whenever I can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Currently, I am working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.co.in/citations?user=qZkww5oAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&#34; target=_blank&gt;Dr. Samar Agnihotri&lt;/a&gt; on my final year Major Technical Project, which is on &lt;b&gt;&#34;Why Deep Learning Works?&#34;&lt;/b&gt;.--&gt;
&lt;!-- My research interests include Deep Learning and Mathematical Computer Science. --&gt; 
&lt;!-- Strong interest in CS and technology led me to become the founder chairperson of ACM-Women Chapter IIT Mandi, that constantly works towards women upliftment in the related fields. --&gt;
&lt;!-- My other hobbies include reading, writing &amp; travelling. I have always been fascinated by the advancements shaping our future and believe that the only attitude that keeps one going is to never stop learning!
--&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World was Hit by a Pandemic!</title>
      <link>https://manvi07.github.io/post/world-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://manvi07.github.io/post/world-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was somewhere in January 2020, when I first heard of a deadly virus called &lt;i&gt;Corona&lt;/i&gt;, affecting numerous people in China. I was in Germany then (semester-exchange) and didn’t bother to give much attention to it, since I was too busy with my course work and in planning trips to beautiful places across Europe, oblivious of the fact that the world is soon going to be under lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-i-at-zürich-during-my-trip-to-switzerland-in-january-2020&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./manvi.jpeg&#34; data-caption=&#34;I, at Zürich during my trip to Switzerland in January 2020.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./manvi.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I, at Zürich during my trip to Switzerland in January 2020.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I completed my semester exams by mid-February 2020 and was to come back to India, when I again heard of the virus, this time, it was called &lt;i&gt;Covid-19&lt;/i&gt; and was a much more serious affair than I had expected in January. The gravity of the matter could be realized from my surroundings, the fear among the people, the mails from the University asking to maintain social distancing and staying alert of any symptoms, and my parents showing concern about me going to the crowded airports. Amidst all this tiny chaos, I had still assumed that the virus won’t be able to cross the China borders.
Airports seemed as usual with some people wearing masks, and some others staring at their strange new look. I was so excited to go back home that there was no room for worry in my mind. From Germany to India with co-passengers from all over the world, I was busy enjoying my window seat, recapitulating all the memories of Europe.
The news of the virus was spreading like fire. Everywhere I went, it was the only topic being discussed, and this process, in some sense, really made me think. Every day, the number of cases in India (and the world) was increasing exponentially, and within a few weeks that I had joined my college in India, we were sent home because of the govt. guidelines keeping in mind the risks of the virus spreading amongst the students. The semester was cut in-between, with no planned alternatives to continue the teaching. Schools and universities were closed in almost all parts of the world for an indefinite time period…&lt;/p&gt;















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-who-declared-covid-19-coronavirus-infection-a-pandemic-credit-tumisu-from-pixabay&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./featured.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;WHO declared Covid-19 coronavirus infection a pandemic. Credit: Tumisu from Pixabay.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    WHO declared Covid-19 coronavirus infection a pandemic. Credit: Tumisu from Pixabay.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The world was hit by a pandemic!&lt;/i&gt; Something, that it had never seen before. Humans were caged in their homes, encountering huge loss, some in terms of money, some in terms of health, and the government trying hard to come up with all kinds of safety measures. The fast and furious pace of life was brought to a halt by a microscopic being.
Technology indeed played a crucial role in these times. MNCs, govt. offices and educational institutes soon adapted to the virtual mode of communication and events (from schooling to weddings) that only used to happen in an in-person mode, were now being held online. Sanitizers and masks became an everyday utility and strict measures were imposed on any kind of gatherings. The world also experienced a time when all the transportation was stopped, local trains as well as international flights.
With technology coming to the rescue in such times, there’s more to ponder upon. The pandemic brought many people home, giving them time to think about the delightful gift of life, that of family and friends, and the need to celebrate their existence every day. This new mode of life has definitely made us stronger and loving, as some people rightly address it as, &lt;i&gt;“nature’s way of reminding humans of &lt;b&gt;humanity!&lt;/b&gt;”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking-Google-Maps Contest Submission</title>
      <link>https://manvi07.github.io/post/hacking-google-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://manvi07.github.io/post/hacking-google-maps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
